Guide to the James H. Laue papers, 1936-1999
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 2: Conflict Resolution Papers, 1967-1993
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Full Session, October 9, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    meeting minutes
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Full Session, November 2, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Full Session, November 15, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Full Session, November 30, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Full Session, December 11, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Full Session, December 20, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Full Session, January 18, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Full Session (Last), March 7, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Full Session Summaries, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Mediation Staff Meetings and Negotiation Training for Team Leaders, October - December 1984 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    NIS, DSS, Lawrence Susskind, Denise Magden
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Negotiation Training / BAIT, July 12, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Notes and Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Process - Personal Questions, Comments, Analysis, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Report Drafts and Notes, part 1, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Report Drafts and Notes, part 2, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Reports from the Mediator, December 1984 - March 1985 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Partnership Forum for Social Service Priorities - Signing Ceremony and Speeches - Team Leaders: Susskind and Matava (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Peace in Action, Vol. 3, No. 2, August 1987 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - "Planning in the Face of Conflict: Mediated Negotiation Strategies in Local Land Use Permitting Processes", undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
    by John Forester, 59 pages
  - "Play Fair" Children's Conflict Resolution Workshop, 1989-1990 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Policy Mediation Summary, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Poverty in America - Miscellaneous Articles, 1970-1986 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - President Carter's Report on the Reform and Restructuring of the United Nations System, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Prison Site Visits - Attica Correctional Facility in New York; Kirkland Correctional Institution in South Carolina; Kentucky Bureau of Corrections, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    memoranda from John Hepburn to James Laue and Martha Becker
  - "Prisoner Redress: Analysis of an Inmate Grievance Procedure", April 1980 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Procedures for Negotiating Proposed Regulations, undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
    Administrative Conference of the United States
  - Proposal for a Pilot Project in School-Based Mediation for Arlington County Public Schools, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Public Private Partnership Program - Mediation Staff Meetings, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    Lawrence Susskind, Massachusetts DSS
  - Reflections of a Social Mediator on the Harvard Conference on Dispute Resolution, Fall 1982 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Religion and Conflict - "Looking Ahead: Beyond Morgenthau" and "Chapter 13: Summing Up", October 31, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - The Religious Community in Social Conflict Resolution: A Workshop at Lindenwood Colleges, St. Charles, Missouri, May 12-13, 1983 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Report of Field Research Activities at Kirkland Correctional Facility and South Carolina Department of Corrections, Columbia, South Carolina, September 26-28, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    memorandum from James Laue to John Hepburn and Martha Becker
  - Resolve No. 19, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    newsletter of the Conservation Foundation
  - Resumes, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - "A Review of the Geneva Negotiations on Strategic Arms Reduction", June 1987 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    by David Cox; the Canadian Institute for International Peace and Security, Background Paper No. 13
  - Rural Mediation Coalition - Mediation of Disputes between Farmers and Lenders, August 1986 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Ruffin / MRA - Caux Scholars Program, 1992-1993 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Rutgers Paper - "Conflict Transformation: Local and Translocal Linkages", April 2-3, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Sermon - "Black Power, White Power, God's Power", February 12, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    Gethsemane Methodist Church
  - Sermon - "Gifts of Peace", 1981-1988 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Sermon - "God, Tobacco Farmer", November 13, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    St. Stephen's
  - Sermon - "Grace and Peacemaking: A Christian View on Conflict Resolution", September 16, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Sermon - Hennepin Ave. United Methodist Church, February 6-8, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Sermon - "In Defense of Creation", December 4, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Sermon - Independence Day / Lincoln, July 5, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Sermon - Laity Day, November - December 1986 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Sermon - "Marks of Wholeness", November 8, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    Susan Thistlethwaite
  - Sermon - Memorial Day and the Prince of Peace, May 24, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Sermon - "Palm Sunday in Belfast, Johannesburg, Moscow, and Jerusalem", April 12, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Sermon - United Methodist Church General Conference, July 1, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    Baltimore, Maryland
  - Sermon - "Xian as Peacemaker", May 7, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    RF, UCC
  - Sermons - Peacemaking, Iran Crisis, etc., 1977-1980 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - "Snow White and the 17 Dwarfs: From Metro Cooperation to Governance", January - February 1987 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    by David B. Walker
  - "Social Change, Dissent, and Violence", 1970 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - "The Social Role of Antagonists and Third-Party Interveners in Violent Confrontations", 1969, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    by John Spiegel, Lemberg Center for the Study of Violence
  - "Societal Violence and Violence in Families", 1977 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Society for International Education, Training, and Research (SIETAR), 1984 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Society of Professionals in Dispute Resolution (SPIDR) - "Making the Tough Calls: Ethical Exercises for Neutral Dispute Resolvers", 1991 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    Anne B. Thomas, editor
  - Solidarity, Vols. III and IV, December 1985 and 1987 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    newsletter of the Committee in Solidarity with Latin American Non-Violent Movements
  - South Africa and Apartheid, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - St. Louis School Desegregation Order, 1978-1980 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    court cases and report of the Center for Metropolitan Studies, University of Missouri, St. Louis
  - Statement by Helmut Kimpel re: World Service Authority, July 23, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Statewide Dispute Resolution Initiatives Compilation, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Strategies and Techniques of Crisis Prevention in Local School Systems, part 1 of 2, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Strategies and Techniques of Crisis Prevention in Local School Systems, part 2 of 2, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - "Strategies to Manage Political Conflict in Northern Ireland in the Eighties: Paradigms or Placebos?", September 1989 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    by Padraig O'Malley
  - A Tentative Comparative Study of Cultural Assumptions Related to Negotiation, December 1987 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Testimony of Dr. David G. Gil, Brandeis University, February 14, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    Congressional Hearings on "Research into Violent Behavior"
  - "Theory and Practice of Negotiated Rulemaking", Fall 1985 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    by Lawrence Susskind and Gerard McMahon, Yale Journal of Regulation
  - "Third Men in New Arenas of Conflict: An Assessment of the Work of the National Center for Dispute Settlement", November 1970 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - "Third Men in New Arenas of Conflict" - Duplicates, November 1970 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - "Third Party Intervention in Community Disputes", August 29, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - "Third Party Intervention in Community Disputes: A Review of the Experience to Date", ca. 1972 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    by Gerald W. Cormick and James Laue
  - "Third Party Intervention: Successful Entry for the Uninvited", 1984 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    by John S. Murray
  - Trinity Forum for International Security and Conflict Resolution - The Central American Peace Process, 1989 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Tucson, Arizona - Conflict Resolution Seminar and Goals for Tucson, part 1 of 2, January - April 1983 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Tucson, Arizona - Conflict Resolution Seminar and Goals for Tucson, part 2 of 2, January - April 1983 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Tucson - Negotiated Investment Strategy (NIS) Speech, February 5, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    contains notes, correspondence, and news clippings
  - Tucson Tomorrow - Notes and Reference Materials, 1978-1983 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - United Methodist Church Council of Bishops, 1988-1989 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    includes materials for a workshop on "The Bishop's Role as Conflict Resolver"
  - Urban Conflict Mediation Book - Chapter Drafts, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - "Urban Conflict: What Role for Negotiations and Mediation?", June 1971 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - "Urban Politics and Poverty: An Analysis of Community Action Programs", 1966 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    prepared by Arthur B. Shostak; 6 pages
  - Urban Solutions Project - KETC-TV / UMSL / UMA Series, 1979-1984 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    contains correspondence, notes, and information on producing a public-access television series
  - U.S. Army Corps of Engineers - Alternative Dispute Resolution Series Pamphlets, 1989-1990 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Army Corps of Engineers - Alternative Dispute Resolution Series Pamphlets, 1989-1992 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Policy and Radical Regimes - Stanley Foundation Vantage Conference, 1986 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Vitarello Development Associates, Inc. - Financing Urban Development, 1986 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - "Waging Peace: Virginia Leads the Way", ca. 1990 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - "Why Liberals Hate 'Single Issues'", April 1980 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    Joh M. Ashbrook, Ohio Senator
  - World Class Exhibition Facilities and Services, ca. 1985 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    International Exposition Center, Cleveland, Ohio
- Series 3: Peace Academy Campaign Papers, 1947-1990, bulk 1976-1990
  This series documents Laue's leading role in the campaign to establish a U.S. Academy of Peace and Conflict Resolution. The series includes public hearings conducted by the Commission on Proposals for the National Academy of Peace, which Laue chaired in 1978-1980; Congressional records and hearings regarding the establishment of the U.S. Academy of Peace; newsletters, brochures, and meeting minutes of the National Peace Academy Campaign (N-PAC), which Laue co-founded in 1976; and various administrative, financial, and promotional materials from the National Peace Academy Foundation / National Peace Institute Foundation (NPAF/NPIF), and the U.S. Academy of Peace / U.S. Institute of Peace (USAP/USIP).
  - Assignment: To Wage Peace, June 1979 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    by Howard B. Christenson
  - Campaign for a U.S. Peace Academy, March 1979 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    by J. David Singer, printed in The Bulletin
  - "Campaign Underway for National Peace Academy", January 1979 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    Newscope
  - Carter Center - International Negotiation Network, 1988 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Commission - Biographic Summaries of Commissioners, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    note: items under the heading "Commission" pertain to the work of the U.S. Commission on Proposals for the National Academy of Peace and Conflict Resolution
  - Commission - Brief Discussion of the Summaries of Witness Testimony, ca. 1980-1981 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Commission - Briefing Seminar, December 1979 - February 1980 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Commission - Budget and Personnel Committee Agenda, December 1979 - January 1980 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Commission - Correspondence, April - June 1979; December 1980 - January 1981 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Commission - Denver; Understanding between CRS and the Commission, February - March 1980 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Commission - Design Paper for the Work of the Commission, March - December 1980 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Commission - Executive Summary, January 1980 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Commission - Executive Summary of Commission Findings, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Commission - Final Report Drafts and Comments, part 1 of 2, December 1980 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Commission - Final Report Drafts and Comments, part 2 of 2, December 1980 - February 1981 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Commission - "Interim Report of the U.S. Commission on Proposals for the National Academy of Peace and Conflict Resolution", 1980 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Commission - Interim Report to Congress and the President, August 1980 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Commission - Introduction of Honorable Spark M. Matsunaga, April 1980 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Commission - Local Research Contacts, 1980 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Commission - Minutes of the First Meeting, December 12, 1979 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Commission - Notes and Correspondence, April - June 1980 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Commission - Notes and Hearings, part 1 of 2, Summer 1980 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Commission - Notes and Hearings, part 2 of 2, Summer 1980 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Commission - Notebook of Commission Findings, part 1 of 2, June - July 1980 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Commission - Notebook of Commission Findings, part 2 of 2, June - July 1980 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Commission - Organizational Meeting, 1979 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Commission - Panelists' Testimony Questions, ca. 1980 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Commission - Proposal for Private Funds to Support the Work of the Commission, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Commission - Public Seminar: Atlanta, Georgia, June 23-24, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Commission - Public Seminar: Boston, Massachusetts, June 2, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Commission - Public Seminar: Boulder, Colorado, March 9-11, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Commission - Public Seminar: Dallas, Texas, June 6-7, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Commission - Public Seminar: Honolulu, Hawaii, part 1 of 2, July 7-8, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Commission - Public Seminar: Honolulu, Hawaii, part 2 of 2 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Commission - Public Seminar: Los Angeles, California, May 12-13, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Commission - Public Seminar: New York, New York, June 196-17, 1980 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Commission - Public Seminar Schedule, March 1980 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Commission - Public Seminar: St. Louis, Missouri, April 21-22, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Commission - Public Seminars, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Commission - Statement by Edward F. Snyder, July 22, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Commission - Statement by James E. Kundle, July 22, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Commission - Statement by John T. Sprout, July 22, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Commission - Statement by Richard C. Williams, Economist, ca. June - July 1980 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Commission - Statement by Robert E. Stein of Environmental Mediation International, ca. July 22, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Commission - Statement by Robert J. Pranger - Outline of Remarks, July 22, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Commission - Statement by the World Federalists Association, July 23, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Commission - Supplemental Briefing Materials, July 17, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Commission - Testimony of Kenneth E. Boulding to Commission, March 10, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Commission - Testimony of Richard D. Fincher and the American Arbitration Association, June 3, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Commission - "To Establish a United States Academy of Peace," Last Outline and First Five Preliminary Chapters, 1981 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Commission - "To Establish a United States Academy of Peace," Outline of the Final Report of the Commission With Notes, 1981 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Commission Timetable, Fall 1980 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Commission - Weekly Briefing Memorandum, March 20, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Commission - Weekly Briefing Memorandum, March 27, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Commission - Witnesses - Biographic Summaries, June 2-3, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Congressional Hearings - "Community Peacemaking: Its Role in a United States Academy for Peace and Conflict Resolution," Testimony from James H. Laue Prepared for Public Hearings on H.R. 10192 and S. 469 to Establish a Commission on Proposals for a U.S. Peace Academy, January 24, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - Congressional Hearings - Correspondence and Materials Regarding H.R. 5088 to Establish a U.S. Academy of Peace, February - May 1982 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Congressional Hearings - "Peace and Conflict Resolution at the Community Level: The Role of Mediators and Other Interveners", May 13, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    Laue's statement for Senate Bill 1976 to establish the George Washington Peace Academy
  - Congressional Hearings - Statement by Bryant Wedge, James Laue, and Lupe Anguiano, January 24, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    transcript recorded by Anderson Reporting Company
  - Congressional Hearings - Statement by Carleton S. Coons, Jr. re: H.R. 10192 to Establish a Commission on Proposals for a U.S. Peace Academy, January 25, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Congressional Hearings - Statement by Gregory B. Wolf re: H.R. 8791 to Establish a Commission on Proposals for a U.S. Peace Academy, January 25, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Congressional Hearings - Statement by Robert Coulson, President of the American Arbitration Association (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Congressional Hearings - Statement by Senator Sparks Matsunaga Supporting H.R. 10192, January 25, 1978 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Congressional Hearings - Testimonial Package from William F. Lincoln re: H.R. 10192, 1975-1978 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Congressional Hearings - Testimony before the Subcommittee on Education, Arts, and Humanities re: S. 1889 and S. 564, part 1 of 2, 1982-1983 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Congressional Hearings - Testimony before the Subcommittee on Education, Arts, and Humanities re: S. 1889 and S. 564, part 1 of 2, 1982-1983 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Congressional Hearings - Testimony before the Subcommittee on International Security and Scientific Affairs re: H.R. 5088, July 20, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Congressional Hearings - Testimony of James H. Laue on H.R. 5088, July 20, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Congressional Hearings - Testimony of James H. Laue on S. 1889, The U.S. Academy of Peace Act, April 21, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Congressional Hearings - Testimony of James H. Laue on S. 564, The Academy of Peace Act, March 16, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Congressional Hearings - Testimony of Robert J. Conlan, Executive Director of the National Peace Institute Foundation, before the Subcommittee on Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, May 15, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Congressional Hearings - "The Uses of a Peace Academy Commission," Statement before the House Subcommittee on International Operations, by Louis Kriesberg, January 1978 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Records and Amendments, part 1 of 3, 1980-1983 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Congressional Records and Amendments, part 2 of 3, 1980-1986 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Congressional Records and Amendments, part 3 of 3, 1977-1981 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Congressional Records and Hearings re: National Academy of Peace, 1975; 1978 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    H.R. 5088, H.R. 6182
  - Congressional Records - George Washington Peace Academy Act, 1975-1976 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    S. 1976
  - Congressional Records - H.R. 1747, S. 469, S. 957, H.R. 10192 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Congressional Records - H.R. 19102 Testimony and Grant Proposals, November 1977 - January 1978 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Records - H.R. 5167 Title IV - U.S. Academy of Peace Act with Proposed Amendments, ca. 1982 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Congressional Records - Proposals to Establish a U.S. Academy of Peace - Joint Hearing, 1982 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Congressional Records - State Resolutions to Establish Peace Institutes, 1982-1985 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Congressional Records - The Situation in El Salvador: Hearings before the Committee on Foreign Relations, U.S. Senate, 1981 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Consortium on Peace Research, Education, and Development (COPRED) - Peace Chronicle, 1988 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Directors of National Peace Groups, ca. 1988 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Ethical Society of St. Louis Event Program, April 8, 1979 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    lists address by Laue titled, "On Penitence and Causing Peace: Are We Ready for a U.S. Academy of Peace and Conflict Resolution?"
  - "A Few Things to Keep in Mind about the Peace Academy", ca. 1978 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - "For a Peace Academy" New York Times Article, July 7 - 1981 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Hubert H. Humphrey Institute of Public Affairs, December 1986 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - International Peace Studies Newsletter, Winter 1979 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Interview with J. N. Moore and James Laue for Peace Institute Reporter, July - October 1986 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - KWMU, "The Subject is Peacemaking", May 1987 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - KWMU, "The Subject is Peacemaking" - Commentary, 1987 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Lentz International Peace Research Award Dinner Invitation, April 20, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Letter to the Editor, Washington Post, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Long Draft of Letters to James Laue and Andrew Young from Bryant Wedge re: Preparing Testimony for House Hearings, November 22, 1976 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - "Marketing Peace", 1979 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    by William J. Spencer
  - Miscellaneous Notes, 1976-1979 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Mississippi Peace Cruise, August 5-8, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Mississippi Peace Cruise, August 5-14, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Monitor Editorial Department re: New York Times Article, September 20, 1979 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    letter from Laue to Henrietta Buckmaster, editor of the Christian Science Monitor's Home Forum page
  - "National Peace Academy: Background and Discussion", February 1978 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    article by Mary Liebman in Prioritas
  - National Peace Academy Campaign (N-PAC) - Action (Steering and Advisory) Committee Meetings, 1977-1978 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    note: N-PAC refers to an official organization working to establish a U.S. Academy of Peace, whereas other files in this series pertain to the peace academy campaign more generally
  - N-PAC Ad Hoc Committee for the National Peace Academy Bill, Summer 1976 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - N-PAC Advisory Committee, July 11, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - N-PAC and Sponsors Invitation to the Mayflower Hotel, February 6, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - N-PAC Annual Report, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - N-PAC - Arguments Commonly Raised Against a Peace Academy, ca. 1978 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - N-PAC - Articles, Clippings, and Correspondence, 1982-1985 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - N-PAC Audited Financial Statements, 1983-1985 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - N-PAC Board Meeting, November 17, 1983 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - N-PAC Board Meeting, April 19, 1984 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - N-PAC - Brief Bibliography, ca. 1978 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - N-PAC Briefing Points on the National Peace Academy, March 1979 (Box 40, Folder 4)